PAUL SPENCER

Software Engineer

+31 6 46 395 141

• Amsterdam, The Netherlands

■ British and Irish (EU)

in linkedin.com/in/spencerpj

spencerpj.com

github.com/McFunshine

Summary

Software engineer with nearly three decades of delivering innovative solutions across fintech, energy, and govtech sectors, including 13 years specialized in .Net technologies. Completed a Master's in Software Engineering in 2022 while maintaining full-time employment. Currently architecting AI and emerging technology solutions while maintaining focus on practical business outcomes. Hardworking, adaptable and committed to continuous professional development.

Experience

Khonraad Software Engineering

Lead AI and Emerging Technologies Architect

 $Amers foort, \ The \ Netherlands \\ Apr \ 2019-Present$

Technologies: Kotlin, Java, C#, Azure, OpenAI, Kotlin Multiplatform, JetBrains MPS, Python

- Developer for production and innovation projects for mental health Laws
- An example innovation project was A RAG chatbot, using .Net and Azure

Captain McFunshines Software Engineering

Freelance Software Engineer

Soest, The Netherlands Aug 2019 – Present

Technologies: Kotlin, Azure, AWS, OpenAI, Kotlin Multiplatform, Python

- Architect and developer of a new audio reversioning platform
- Five-month .Net consultancy engagement with Baker Hughes

Baker Hughes

 $Senior\ . Net\ Developer$

Delft, The Netherlands Jan 2014 - Apr 2019

Technologies: C#, SQL Server

- Member of team that developed the SDK and API for the JewelSuite platform
- Served as principal technical contact for external developers building JewelSuite extensions
- Senior .Net contractor, managing quality and delivery of an offshore team

Kempen & Co

Senior .Net Developer

Amsterdam, The Netherlands May 2007 – Dec 2013

Technologies: C#, K2, SQL Server, VBA

- Delivered training on Entity Framework, Linq and Unit Testing/TDD
- Maintained and enhanced property securities indexing engine
- Developed application for maintaining and trading complex structured products
- Authored K2 Workflow (WWF) systems of business-critical processes

Unisys

Developer

Developer

Technologies: VBA, WebIntelligence, C#

- Reporting developer for world wide Accounts Receivables

- Achieved first Microsoft Certification and implemented small internal C# projects

ACT Financial Systems

London, UK

 $Nov \ 1999-Apr \ 2001$

Schiphol Rijk, The Netherlands

May 2001 - May 2007

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe, Visual Basic 6

- Developer and supporting Engineer for a stockbroking settlement system

- Thirdline support for OMS a Visual Basic 6 wrapper on our settlement system

HSBC Investment Bank

London, UK

Developer Feb 1999 – Nov 1999

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe

- Developer for message processing, report writing, and screen handling programs

Lloyds Bank Stockbrokers

London, UK

Support / Business Analyst

May 1997 - Feb 1999

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe, VBA, Visual Basic 4

- Support and Report Developer for internal customers

- Took Visual Basic 4 night classes and thereafter implemented small internal projects

Education

Universiteit van Amsterdam

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Masters Software Engineering

Graduated 2022

Relevant Module: Software Construction - I created two interacting Domain Specific Languages using C# Note: Completed while maintaining full-time employment

Wolverhampton University

Wolverhampton, U.K.

BA European Business Administration

Graduated 1996

Hogeschool Holland

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

HEAO Joint European Business Administration

 $Graduated\ 1996$

Certifications

The Following Microsoft Professional Certifications:

- MCPD D425-8639 Windows Developer
- MCPD D418-3946 Windows Azure Developer (Charter Member)
- MCPD D415-8350 Web Developer
- MCPD A941-2480 Windows Developer
- MCPD A941-2479 Web Developer
- MCT D423-9678 .NET Framework, Windows Applications
- MCT D413-5519 .NET Framework, Data Access
- MCT D410-3346 . NET Framework, Web Applications
- MCT D404-5594 .NET Framework, Service Communication
- MCT A941-2481 . NET Framework, Windows Applications
- MCT A941-2482 . NET Framework, Web Applications
- MCSD C020-3599 Microsoft . NET
- MCAD C020-3597 Microsoft .NET
- MCP D020-3593 Microsoft Certified Professional
- Nederlands Als Een Tweede Taal (NT2) Niveau 2

Languages

- **English:** Mother Tongue
- Dutch: Fluent spoken, listening and reading, intermediate written